[Music]
foreign
ancient Greece the art of medicine was
divided into three areas cures through
diet cures through drugs and cures
through surgery
garlic Hippocrates wrote was one such
medicinal food but that was to treat a
non-existent entity called displacement
of the womb so ancient wisdom can only
go so far those who eat more than a
clove a day do seem to have better
artery functions those who eat less than
a clove a day but you don't know if it's
cause and effect until you
put it to the test
heart disease patients were randomized
to receive either garlic powder or
Placebo tablets twice daily for three
months and those lucky enough to be in
the garlic group got a significant boost
in their artery function a 50 increase
in function taking only 800 milligrams
of garlic powder a day it's just a
quarter teaspoon of garlic powder a 50
increase in ordering function for less
than a penny a day
if regular plain boring garlic powder
can do that what about those fancy
Kyolic aged garlic extract supplements
30 times more expensive and they don't
work at all four weeks and zero
significant Improvement it's hard to
improve on Mother Nature
garlic powder can improve the function
of arteries but what about the structure
of Our arteries dozens of studies on
garlic all compiled together show garlic
can reduce cholesterol levels in the
blood by more than 16 points so my
garlic powder be able to actually slow
the progression of atherosclerosis
garlic powder tablet versus placebo for
three months the placebo group got worse
which is what tends to happen to eat the
same artery clogging diet in your
arteries continue to clog but the
progression of the disease appeared to
slow and stall in the garlic group
of course it'd be nice to see the artery
wall thickening actually reverse but for
that one might have to add more plants
than just garlic to one's diet
still though that same quarter teaspoon
of a simple spice available anywhere may
be considered as an adjunct treatment
for atherosclerosis the number one
killer both men and women in the United
States and around much of the world
what about garlic for high blood
pressure systematic review and
meta-analysis of randomized control
trials demonstrating garlic as a
statistically significant and clinically
meaningful effect on both systoc and
diastolic blood pressure reducing the
top number by nearly seven of the bottom
number by about five may not sound like
a lot but reducing diastolic blood
pressure the bottom number by Five
Points can reduce the risk of Stroke by
about a third and heart disease by 25
percent
plant-based medicine can provide
beneficial effects with little or no
side effects and compared to other
medicine relatively cost effective I'd
say so at as little as a penny per day
[Music]
thank you